<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Octopress | Juani Villarejo's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jonvillage.com/blog/blog/categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jonvillage.com/blog/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-26T19:23:37-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://jonvillage.com/blog/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Juani Villarejo]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[contact@jonvillage.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Setting Up an Octopress Blog on Github Pages]]></title>
    <link href="http://jonvillage.com/blog/2013/12/30/setting-up-an-octopress-blog-on-github-pages/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T15:01:12-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://jonvillage.com/blog/2013/12/30/setting-up-an-octopress-blog-on-github-pages</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Suppose you are already hosting your personal site in github pages with your user name, so when you go to <a href="http://yourusername.github.io,">http://yourusername.github.io,</a> or <a href="http://yourcustomdomain.com">http://yourcustomdomain.com</a> if you had set up a custom domain, the page that gets renderer is your home page with your portfolio, social links and contact form.</p>

<p>However you want to have your own personal blog hosted in github pages too but this time pointing to <a href="http://yourcustomdomain/blog">http://yourcustomdomain/blog</a> so let&rsquo;s configure octopress in order to have that.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t know about octopress, octopress is a blog framework that let&rsquo;s you create blog posts as a static page instead of a full dynamic page like wordpress, it is simpler because it doesn&rsquo;t need any database or special server, and you can host your blog on gh-pages as it is a static web page</p>

<p>More info:
<a href="http://octopress.org/">http://octopress.org/</a></p>

<h2>Let&rsquo;s get our hands dirty</h2>

<p>First let&rsquo;s clone octopress framework</p>

<p><code>
$ git clone git://github.com/imathis/octopress.git octopress
</code></p>

<p>Now we want to point to our own github repository, so create your repository project repository on github and then</p>

<p><code>
$ git remote rm origin
$ git remote add origin your_repository
</code>
Where it says your_repository it should be the project repository you just created.
After this we want to download all the gems that octopress uses, thankfully it comes with bundler</p>

<p><code>
$ bundle install
</code></p>

<p>Then we have to tell octopress to create all the needed folders</p>

<p><code>
$ rake install
</code></p>

<p>This is a good point to commit all our changes to our repository</p>

<p><code>
$ git add -A .
$ git commit -m "Initial setup"
</code></p>

<p>Now we need to configure octopress to use github pages</p>

<p><code>
$ rake setup_github_pages  
</code></p>

<p>Copy and paste your github repository on the promt when asked for it.</p>

<p>We are almost there, so we have to configure octopress to be published on /blog in order to do that we have to change the root directory</p>

<p><code>
$ rake set_root_dir[/blog]
</code></p>

<p>And then we have to change the url in the the _config.yml file, note that if you have a custom domain like for example jonvillage.com you have to put that there, if you don&rsquo;t want a custom domain and want to use your github url it would be just yourusername.github.io/blog</p>

<p>Also we need to change the permalink to display your posts in the correct url</p>

<p>```
url: <a href="http://yoururl/blog">http://yoururl/blog</a></p>

<p>permalink: /:year/:month/:day/:title/
```</p>

<p>The _config.yml file lets you configure the blog title, subtitle and more.</p>

<p>Now we need to generate all the pages and commit everything to your repository master</p>

<p><code>
$ rake generate
$ git add -A .
$ git commit -m "Successfuly configured blog"
</code></p>

<p>The finishing touch</p>

<p><code>
rake deploy
</code></p>

<p>Now go to <a href="http://yoururl/blog">http://yoururl/blog</a> and you can see it</p>

<p>I hope you liked it and could deploy it, if you have any further question just ask and I will answer as soon as I can</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
